Mo Pishdar

Chatswood, NSW 2067
Phone: 0404786047 | Email: mohpish@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammadpishdar/ | GitHub:
https://github.com/Mohammad-Pishdar | Portfolio: https://mohammad-pishdar.github.io/responsive-portfolio/

Summary

Full stack web developer specialising in mobile-first website design leveraging the power of React to create interactive UIs. Ability to create responsive web page layouts using HTML and CSS while utilising the full power of Google Chrome dev tools for real time debugging. Proven JavaScript and jQuery API skills that enhances UX, bringing the UI to life through added functionality, creating servers for the backend using node and express.js and database creation and management using MongoDB. Certificate from the Coding Boot Camp at the University of Sydney. Involved in the design of a fully responsive job search website with dynamically generated content and saved search history utilising HTML, CSS (Pure framework) and JS (jQuery) as the core technologies. Strong analytical and problem solving (data analysis and research) with expert organisation skills gained from working as a senior research agronomist.

Technical Skills

Web Development Core Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

CSS Frameworks: Bootstrap, Pure

JavaScript Frameworks: jQuery, Node.js, React JS

Web Development Essential Techniques: Version Control (Git), Browser developer tools (Google Chrome dev tools) for testing and debugging, Web Performance (Lighthouse),

Restful APIs

Database Management Tools and Techniques: MySQL server, MongoDB, ORMs,

Sequelize

Projects

Mina Plant Sale | Repo: https://bit.ly/359mOWR | Deployed: https://bit.ly/3lcEsid

- A real-word online store that not only lets clients buy items online and pay using PayPal, but also have admin features.
- This was an individual effort as the final project for the bootcamp.
- Tools used: The full MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React and Node.js)

Game JAM | Repo: https://bit.ly/33NbDIW | Deployed: https://bit.ly/378xKWn

- A searchable database that allows users to find information about major video game releases, including copies sold and review scores.
- Responsible for defining API routes, creating Sequelize models, populating data tables in MySQL and writing JavaScript models
- Tools used: Bootstrap, jQuery, Node.is, Express.is and Sequelize

Job Search App | Repo: https://bit.ly/30VfonH | Deployed: https://bit.ly/3nC16Ch

 A Job search application that runs in the browser and renders results for jobs in the UK dynamically based on the keywords and filters provided by the user while keeping a search history for later use.

- Responsible for writing JavaScript code to retrieve required data based on provided keywords and filters via the Adzuna API and all the functionalities of different buttons and checkboxes, search history and local storage settings.
- Tools used: Bootstrap and Pure as CSS libraries, jQuery, Adzuna job search API and Google Books API

Experience

Kitchen Assistant 2018 – Present 465 The Avenue Chatswood, NSW

- Maintain the kitchen in a presentable fashion through organisation of daily tasks based on immediate priorities
- Supervise the delivery of supplies for two major delivery days a week with more than 30 kinds of delivery items to store and organise
- Storeroom stocking

Kitchen Assistant 2016 – 2018 **Ground Espresso** North Sydney, NSW

- Set up the café ready for opening
- Maintain the kitchen and café area in a presentable fashion
- Organise chores based on immediate priorities
- Serve breakfast to an average of 50 customers a day in a fast-paced and efficient manner
- Supervise the delivery of kitchen supplies

Pastry Kitchen Hand 2014 – 2016 Bathers Pavilion Mosman, NSW

- Clean the kitchen area
- Operate and maintain the dish washing machines
- Prepare food and storing in the storehouse

Research Agronomist 2005 – 2014 Safiabad Agricultural Research Centre Dezful, Iran

- Supervise a team of 5 field workers and 2 technicians to manage fields
- Propose and conduct 20 of field trials
- Work with international organisations (ICARDA and CIMMYT) as a part of a team of quality crops development and localisation
- Prepare final reports, present the results and recommendations, and publish 3 articles in scientific journals and congresses.

Education

The Coding Bootcamp Certificate: University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW

A comprehensive 24-week coding bootcamp for full-stack web development featuring the latest in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, various frameworks and libraries, version control, debugging and testing procedures, database management and server-side technologies.

Intro to Programming Nanodegree: Udacity via Udacity online platform

A 4-month program to learn the fundamentals of programming through HTML, CSS, and Python to develop thinking and problem-solving habits of a programmer.

Business Analytics Fundamentals: Babson College via Edx online platform

A 4-week introduction to business analytics featuring data analysis, sampling and estimation, hypothesis testing, linear models, and regression models.

MSc. Of Agronomy: Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz, Iran

Bachelor's degree of Agronomy and Plant Breeding: Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz, Iran